A Guide to the Margaret Williams Papers, 1970-1985
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Margaret Williams Papers, 1970-1985
Library of Virginia
32504
2.45 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Margaret Williams, Alexandria, Virginia, in 1985.
Biographical Information
Born in 1953 in Norfolk, Virginia, Margaret "Meg" Williams was an active member of the Virginia Women's Political Caucus from 1971-1976. She also served on a number of other women's organizations including the Women's Lobby and co-authored The Almanac of Virginia Politics, 1977-1985. A full biographical vita compiled in 1985 is included in the collection.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1970-1985, of Margaret "Meg" Williams (1953-) principally consisting of correspodence, speeches, printed resource materials, newspaper clippings, writings, and General Assembly bills pertaining to women. This material generally concerns Williams' activities as a woman's activist in Virginia during the 1970's and early 1980's.
Arrangement
Organized into the following four series: I. Biographical Information and Writings, 1972, 1985; II. Organizational Files, 1971-1985; III. Subject Files, 1970-1982; IV. General Assembly Bills, 1972-1978.
Contents List
- Biographical Information and Writings, 1972, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Consists of a full biographical vita compiled in 1985, a newspaper article concerning Meg Williams dated 1972, and a scholarly paper written by Williams.
- Organizational Files, 1971-1985 (Box 1, Folders 2-15)
  Contains information related to Meg Williams' involvement with the Equal Rights Amendment Ratification Council, the Richmond chapter of the National Organization for Women, Women's Lobby Inc., STOP ERA, Virginia ERA Central, and the Virginia Women's Political Caucus.
  Arranged alphabetically by organization's name.
  - ERA Ratification Council, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Organization for Women, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - STOP ERA, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Virginia ERA Central, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - general (organizational), 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - general, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - appointments, 1972-1973, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - appointments (rosters), 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - candidate questionnaires, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - lobbying, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - lobbying (printed material), 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - rape, 1972-1976, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus - rape, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Women's Lobby, Inc., 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Subject Files, 1970-1982 (Box-folder Box 1, Folders 16-19 - Box 2, Folders 1-5)
  Includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, printed material concerning subjects pertaining to women's rights in the 1970's including abortion, the Equal Rights Amendment both nationally and in Virginia, the Feminist Movement, job descrimination and equal pay, Title IX and equality in sports, and equality in economics.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abortion, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ERA, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ERA - Virginia, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ERA - Virginia, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Feminism - general, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Job discrimination - equal pay, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Magazines, 1970-1972, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Title IX - sports in higher education, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Women's National Bank - Women As Economic Equals Conference, 1973-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- General Assembly Bills, 1972-1978 (Box 2-3)
  Consists of printed Virginia General Assembly bills pertaining to women's issues.